- [Instructor] Now let's finalize the code for the form
by adding all the proper functions required
and testing the application.
Again, as I noted, I've only added a few elements fields
for our players, but only to make sure
you're not going to see me doing all these elements
on screen, which are repetitive.
Feel free to add them yourselves on your application.
Okay, so let's continue working on our form here.
And what I'm going to start adding
is the actual submit player function here.
So let's go ahead and do this.
So I'm going to add a function.
Whenever there's an event,
first of all, we're going to preventDefault().
And then what I'm going to do is use axios to post
to our front end.
So again, if you're doing this in the cloud,
if you're sending your backend into the cloud,
you want to make sure that the URL that you're using here
is the proper URL.
In this case, I'm using my local install.
So I'm going to do localhost:4000.
And again, remember the endpoint,
we're using players here as the endpoint to do a post.
And then we're going to pass in this post command
what we have here.
So first, we're going to use a first name.
Remember, it requires a first name.
If you want to go back to the backend that we've built,
you require absolutely a first name.
So what I'm going to do is use the refs, this.refs.
First name and the value from that form.
And do the exact same thing for each of the element
that I have on my form.
So I'm going to do this four times.
This is going to be the last name.
Then we're going to have here and here the phone first.
And then the email, like so.
So we're going to do a post.
Then what we're going to do use then,
we're going to get the response
and we're going to console.log it, just for time being.
That's what we're going to do.
Just to make sure we have some way
of checking that this has worked.
Otherwise, if anything goes wrong,
catch the error and pass the error console.log.
I should have done the exact same above.
I'm going to do that here to remove that curly brace here.
Make it shorter, like so.
There you go.
We don't need the extra curly braces here.
Okay, so what we're doing, we're submitting player,
we're going to call this shortly from the form.
We prevent the default
so we're not automatically switching to another page.
Then what we're doing is basically using axios
to post through our backend to the endpoint players
forwarding the first name, last name,
phone, and email to the backend
with the references that we have inside of our form.
And again, like I mentioned before,
if you want to use the new method here,
you can do that as well.
Then we're calling a response,
we're sending that response to console.log,
or we're catching the error
and sending that to the console.log as well.
Okay, so now we need to make sure
that we're using that function inside of our form.
So let's make sure we do that here.
So onSubmit=
and we want to bind this as well
just to make sure that it's working inside of React.
Okay, now everything is updated.
Let's close this.
Let's go to our application here.
I'm just going to refresh it just to be sure.
We're going to select the player first.
And we need to finalize this in the next video.
I just realized that we have one more video
to actually finalize the loading of the player here.
What I'm going to do now is add a new player.
So first name, I'm going to call this,
we don't have Manuello in the database now.
So Manuello Henritto.
Phone: 44455512345, or let's do 9.
Email: me4@me4.com. Okay.
So I click ADD PLAYER.
I'm just going to open my terminal
just to make sure I'm seeing the response here
as I submit.
Add player and hold on.
Axios: Request failed with status code, okay.
There's some cross references here.
Okay, so what I'm going to do is check all this
and we're going to fix this in the next video.